<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><idinfo><keywords><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt><themekey>boundaries</themekey><themekey>environment</themekey><themekey>location</themekey><themekey>oceans</themekey><themekey>planningCadastre</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>EPA GIS Keyword Thesaurus</themekt><themekey>Biology</themekey><themekey>Compliance</themekey><themekey>Conservation</themekey><themekey>Ecology</themekey><themekey>Ecosystem</themekey><themekey>Environment</themekey><themekey>Human</themekey><themekey>Management</themekey><themekey>Marine</themekey><themekey>Monitoring</themekey><themekey>Natural Resources</themekey><themekey>Permits</themekey><themekey>Regulatory</themekey><themekey>Water</themekey></theme><place><placekt>None</placekt><placekey>Atlantic Ocean</placekey><placekey>Georges Bank</placekey><placekey>Greater Atlantic Region</placekey><placekey>Gulf of Maine</placekey><placekey>New England</placekey><placekey>Southern New England</placekey><placekey>United States</placekey><placekey>US EEZ</placekey><placekey>US Exclusive Economic Zone</placekey></place><theme><themekt>GARFO Keywords</themekt><themekey>ALWTRP</themekey><themekey>Atlantic</themekey><themekey>Atlantic Large Whale Take Reduction Plan</themekey><themekey>EEZ</themekey><themekey>Exclusive Economic Zone</themekey><themekey>GARFO</themekey><themekey>Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office</themekey><themekey>Marine Mammal Protection Act</themekey><themekey>MMPA</themekey><themekey>National Marine Fisheries Service</themekey><themekey>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</themekey><themekey>NMFS</themekey><themekey>NOAA</themekey><themekey>US EEZ</themekey></theme></keywords><citation><citeinfo><origin>NOAA Fisheries Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office</origin><title>Great South Channel Restricted Gillnet Area and GSC Sliver Restricted Area</title><pubinfo><publish>NOAA National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS) - Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office (GARFO)</publish><pubplace>Gloucester, MA</pubplace></pubinfo><pubdate>20150605</pubdate><onlink>http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/gis</onlink><onlink>http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/</onlink></citeinfo></citation><timeperd><current>Publication date</current><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20150605</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-80</westbc><eastbc>-64</eastbc><northbc>46</northbc><southbc>32</southbc></bounding></spdom><accconst>None.</accconst><useconst>*** Attribution *** Whenever NMFS material is reproduced and re-disseminated, we request that users attribute the material appropriately.  Pursuant to 17 U.S.C. 403, parties who produce copyrighted works consisting predominantly of material created by the Federal Government are encouraged to provide notice with such work(s) identifying the U.S. Government material incorporated and stating that such material is not subject to copyright protection. Please cite Regulated Area datasets as follows, with the appropriate information substituted for all text in {CURLY BRACKETS}:
NOAA Fisheries Service. NMFS Regulated Areas in Northeast and Mid-Atlantic Waters.  {SHAPEFILE TITLE} [Shapefile]. Gloucester, MA: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office (GARFO) [producer] {SHAPEFILE PUBLICATION DATE}. http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/gis.
*** No Warranty*** The user assumes the entire risk related to its use of these data. NMFS is providing these data "as is," and NMFS disclaims any and all warranties, whether express or implied, including (without limitation) any implied warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose. No warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the accuracy or utility of the data on any other system or for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. It is strongly recommended that careful attention be paid to the contents of the metadata file associated with these data to evaluate dataset limitations, restrictions or intended use.  In no event will NMFS be liable to you or to any third party for any direct, indirect, incidental, consequential, special or exemplary damages or lost profit resulting from any use or misuse of this data.
*** Proper Usage *** The information on government servers are in the public domain, unless specifically annotated otherwise, and may be used freely by the public. Before using information obtained from this server, special attention should be given to the date and time of the data and products being displayed. This information shall not be modified in content and then presented as official government material.
This dataset was created to depict the boundaries of NMFS Regulated Areas in Northeast and Mid-Atlantic Waters (Regulated Areas) only.  The dataset should not be used for a legal definition.  The dataset should not be used to infer information regarding the existence or details of other marine features or resources, including, but not limited to, navigable waters, coastlines, bathymetry, submerged features, or man-made structures.  Users assume responsibility for determining the appropriate use of this dataset.
*** Not the Legal Definition *** This Geographic Information System (GIS) dataset is not the legal definition of the Regulated Area. The description published in the U.S. Code of Federal Regulations is the only legal definition.  This dataset and metadata document provide a broad overview of a subset of applicable fishing regulations, restrictions and requirements; it is not a substitute for the actual regulations. Users are encouraged to read the applicable regulations in conjunction with use of this dataset.  
*** Temporal Considerations *** Regulated Area boundary definitions are subject to change or modification.  Published datasets may represent historic, current, or future Regulated Areas.  When changes to fishing regulations affect this dataset, it will be archived and replaced by an updated version as soon as feasible.  Approved Regulated Area boundaries may also be published prior to their effective date.  It is the user’s responsibility to ensure the applicable Regulated Area boundaries are being used.  
*** Shorelines/Base Layers *** The accuracy of this dataset is dependent upon the accuracy and resolution of the datasets (e.g., shoreline, bathymetry, shared administrative boundaries) used in the creation process. Source datasets used are specified in the metadata.  These data sources were selected for their suitability to a broad audience, and may not be suitable for specific uses requiring higher-resolution information. 
Coastlines change.  Unless otherwise noted, where the NOAA Medium Resolution Shoreline is used, assume the regulatory boundary reaches the most current coastline delineation available.</useconst><descript><abstract>This dataset depicts the boundaries of the Great South Channel Restricted Gillnet Area and GSC Sliver Restricted Area in ESRI shapefile format for the NOAA Fisheries Service’s Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office (GARFO).  This shapefile includes boundaries for the following Regulated Areas:
 - Great South Channel Restricted Gillnet Area
 - Great South Channel Sliver Restricted Area

Because GIS projection and topology functions can change or generalize coordinates, these GIS files are considered to be approximate representations and are NOT an OFFICIAL record for the exact regulated area boundaries.  For information on the official legal definition refer to the Use Constraints metadata section.</abstract><purpose>Beginning in 2010 and in response to mounting requests for digital depictions of NMFS Regulated Areas in Northeast and Mid-Atlantic Waters (Regulated Areas), the NMFS Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office (GARFO) Geographic Information Systems (GIS) Committee launched a project to standardize the development, publication and regular updating of GIS files depicting Regulated Area boundaries.  This dataset is a product of that initiative. 

This dataset was created to depict the boundaries of NMFS Regulated Areas in Northeast and Mid-Atlantic Waters (Regulated Areas) only.  For information on the proper use of the dataset refer to the Use Constraints metadata section.</purpose></descript><secinfo><secsys>FIPS Pub 199</secsys><secclass>No Confidentiality</secclass><sechandl>Standard Technical Controls</sechandl></secinfo><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>NOAA Fisheries Service Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office, Protected Resources Division</cntorg><cntper>Michael Asaro</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Committee Protected Resources Representative</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>55 Great Republic Drive</address><city>Gloucester</city><state>MA</state><postal>01930</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>978-282-8469</cntvoice><cntfax>978-281-9394</cntfax><cntemail>michael.asaro@noaa.gov</cntemail><cntinst>http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/</cntinst></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><logic>Check Geometry test has been performed in ArcGIS.</logic><complete>Features represented are valid.  No geometry problems were detected.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Data were collected using methods that are accurate to within 2-5 meters (EPA National Geospatial Data Policy [NGDP] Accuracy Tier 2). For more information, please see EPA's NGDP at http://epa.gov/geospatial/policies.html</horizpar></horizpa></posacc><lineage><procstep><procdate>2015</procdate><procdesc>[Get Definition Text] The current legal spatial definition for the Regulated Area was copied from the e-CFR website.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2015</procdate><procdesc>[Features, No Template]  To generate the Regulated Area boundary in ArcGIS, the coordinates were connected in the order specified in the spatial definition.  When multiple Regulated Areas are a part of a larger grouping of related Regulated Areas, these steps were repeated to generate a unique feature for each Regulated Area and the features were then combined into a single shapefile.  When the spatial definition specified that points were connected by following a straight line, rhumb lines were constructed by projecting the shapefile into a NAD83 Mercator projection, which maintains straight rhumbs.  The boundaries were densified with consecutive vertices interpolated no more than 10 nautical miles apart, to preserve rhumb line paths in other coordinate systems. The file was projected back to the un-projected NAD83 coordinate system.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2015</procdate><procdesc>[Add Attributes] The standardized attribute schema was applied to the shapefile, and the fields were defined.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2015</procdate><procdesc>[Policy Review] The Regulated Area spatial definition text, shapefile geometry and attribute values were reviewed with policy staff to verify that the shapefile accurately depicted and described the intended boundaries.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2015</procdate><procdesc>[Check Geometry] The ESRI ArcGIS Check Geometry tool was run on the shapefile to identify any geometry problems.  If problems were encountered, they were reviewed and corrected.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2015</procdate><procdesc>[Metadata] A GARFO Regulated Area shapefile metadata template was developed using the EPA Metadata Editor v3.2.  This template was applied and customized to reflect the specific characteristics of the given shapefile.  The metadata was validated for FGDC CSDGM compliance.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>2015</procdate><procdesc>[Final Review] The shapefile was reviewed by members of the GARFO GIS Committee, policy experts from the GARFO Division responsible for the Regulated Area, and General Counsel, according to the GARFO GIS Data Distribution Policy.</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>20150605</procdate><procdesc>[Publication] The shapefile, with accompanying metadata, was uploaded for public download on the NOAA NMFS GARFO GIS website.</procdesc></procstep><srcinfo><typesrc>online</typesrc><srccitea>e-CFR</srccitea><srccontr>Spatial definitions for Regulated Area boundaries.</srccontr><srctime><srccurr>publication date</srccurr><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>1998</begdate><enddate>present</enddate></rngdates></timeinfo></srctime><srccite><citeinfo><origin>Department of Commerce (DOC), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS)</origin><title>Electronic Code of Federal Regulations</title><edition>Special Edition of the Federal Register</edition><geoform>document</geoform><othercit>The Electronic Code of Federal Regulations (e-CFR) is a current, daily updated version of the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR). It is not an official legal edition of the CFR. The e-CFR is an unofficial editorial compilation of CFR material and Federal Register amendments.  Because the e-CFR is updated daily, the PUBLICATION DATE identified above refers to "e-CFR Data is current as of" date posted on the e-CFR website at the time the spatial definition was accessed online.</othercit><pubdate>20150508</pubdate><pubinfo><publish>Office of the Federal Register, National Archives and Records Administration and the Government Printing Office</publish><pubplace>Washington, DC</pubplace></pubinfo><onlink>http://www.ecfr.gov</onlink></citeinfo></srccite></srcinfo></lineage></dataqual><spref><horizsys><geograph><latres>0.000001</latres><longres>0.000001</longres><geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit></geograph><geodetic><horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn><ellips>Geodetic Reference System 1980</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222</denflat></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>Regulated Area</enttypl><enttypd>NMFS Regulated Areas in Northeast and Mid-Atlantic Waters</enttypd><enttypds>GARFO</enttypds></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>FID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>System-generated internal feature number</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinate geometry</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>GARFO_ID</attrlabl><attrdef>A unique identifier used to identify and track this feature; a new GARFO_ID is generated for each version of a Regulated Area (i.e. whenever boundaries or attributes are changed, edited or updated)</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>System-generated number</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREANAME</attrlabl><attrdef>Official name of the Regulated Area, usually the area name as printed in the CFR</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>COMMNAME</attrlabl><attrdef>Most commonly used name.  May be identical to AREANAME, an abbreviation of AREANAME, or a different name altogether.</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREAGROUP</attrlabl><attrdef>Specifies if the Regulated Area is part of a group of related areas</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>DESCRIBE</attrlabl><attrdef>A brief description of the purpose of the Regulated Area</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text description</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRTITLE</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Title citation where the Regulated Area is legally defined</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRPT</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Part citation where the Regulated Area is legally defined</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text citation</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRPTTXT</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Part citation header text</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRSUB</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Subpart citation where the Regulated Area is legally defined</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text citation</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRSUBTXT</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Subpart citation header text</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRSXN</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Section citation where the Regulated Area is legally defined</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text citation</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRSXNTXT</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Section citation header text</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRPARA</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Paragraph citation where the Regulated Area is legally defined</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text citation</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CFRPARATXT</attrlabl><attrdef>CFR Paragraph citation header text</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>FRCITE</attrlabl><attrdef>Federal Register citation of original Regulated Area spatial definition, or last modification to the spatial definition, whichever is most recent.  Refers to SPATIAL DEFINITION ONLY.  Subsequent FR notices may have modified the requirements affecting waters within or outside this Regulated Area.</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>FRDATE</attrlabl><attrdef>Federal Register citation date of original Regulated Area spatial definition, or the last modification to the spatial definition, whichever is most recent.  Refers to SPATIAL DEFINITION ONLY.  Subsequent FR notices may have modified the requirements affecting waters within or outside this Regulated Area.</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>EFFECTDATE</attrlabl><attrdef>Date Regulated Area officially became law, or most recent modification</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SOURCE</attrlabl><attrdef>If Regulated Area is defined in the CFR, this is the citation for the Amendment/Framework/etc. that established the area.  If the Regulated Area is not defined in the CFR, this is the alternative source citation establishing the Regulated Area.</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text citation</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>RECURST</attrlabl><attrdef>Annually recurring date Regulated Area becomes active</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>RECUREND</attrlabl><attrdef>Annually recurring date Regulated Area becomes inactive</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>GISAUTHOR</attrlabl><attrdef>Name of the NOAA staff person who created the GIS feature</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Name</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>CREATED</attrlabl><attrdef>Creation date of the GIS feature</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREANOTES</attrlabl><attrdef>Miscellaneous notes regarding the Regulated Area or feature</attrdef><attrdefs>GARFO</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Free text description</udom></attrdomv></attr></detailed><overview><eaover>Entity Attributes provide reference information for the Regulated Areas represented.  Attributes provide citations for the legal spatial definition and originating documents, and currentness information for each area.</eaover><eadetcit>FILEDS_Map.xlsx fully describes the Attribute Schema used for regulated area GIS data sets.  To access this document, see the Contact Information.</eadetcit></overview></eainfo><distinfo><resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc><distliab>The user assumes the entire risk related to use of these data. NMFS is providing these data "as is," and NMFS disclaims any and all warranties, whether express or implied, including (without limitation) any implied warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose. No warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the accuracy or utility of the data on any other system or for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. It is strongly recommended that careful attention be paid to the contents of the metadata file associated with these data to evaluate dataset limitations, restrictions or intended use.  In no event will NMFS be liable to you or to any third party for any direct, indirect, incidental, consequential, special or exemplary damages, or lost profit resulting from any use or misuse of this data</distliab><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>NOAA Fisheries Service Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office, GIS Committee</cntorg><cntper>Dean-Lorenz Szumylo</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>55 Great Republic Drive</address><city>Gloucester</city><state>MA</state><postal>01930</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>978-282-8479</cntvoice><cntfax>978-281-9333</cntfax><cntemail>dean.szumylo@noaa.gov</cntemail><cntinst>http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/</cntinst></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20150605</metd><metfrd>20190605</metfrd><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>NOAA Fisheries Service Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office, GIS Committee</cntorg><cntper>Dean-Lorenz Szumylo</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>55 Great Republic Drive</address><city>Gloucester</city><state>MA</state><postal>01930</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>978-282-8479</cntvoice><cntfax>978-281-9333</cntfax><cntemail>dean.szumylo@noaa.gov</cntemail><cntinst>http://www.greateratlantic.fisheries.noaa.gov/</cntinst></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct></spdoinfo><distInfo><distTranOps><transSize>0.028</transSize></distTranOps></distInfo><Esri><DataProperties><copyHistory><copy source="C:\Users\Dean.Szumylo\Desktop\telework\ALWTRP_April_2019_Meeting\geodata\2_development\Great_South_Channel_Sliver_Restricted_Area" dest="\\NERLIRM5MDVJ02\C$\Users\Dean.Szumylo\Desktop\telework\ALWTRP_April_2019_Meeting\geodata\2_development\ALWTRP_Areas_for_April_2019_Meeting\Great_South_Channel_Sliver_Restricted_Area" date="20190329" time="12555900"></copy></copyHistory></DataProperties></Esri></metadata>
